<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="urn:x-suse:xslt:profiling:docbook50-profile.xsl"
 type="text/xml"
 title="Profiling step"?>
<!DOCTYPE article
[
  <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
    %entities;
]>
<?provo dirname="faqs/"?>
<article version="5.1" xml:lang="en" xml:id="art.caas.faqs"
 xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
 <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
 <subtitle>&productname; &productnumber;</subtitle>
 <info>
  <productnumber>&productnumber;</productnumber><productname>&productname;</productname><date>
<?dbtimestamp format="B d, Y"?></date>
</info> 

<qandaset>
 <qandaentry>
  <question>
   <para>
    How can I obtain and install &productname;? 
   </para>
  </question>
  <answer>
   You can download the <literal>iso</literal> image from ... and then proceed as described in <xref linkend="art.caasp.quickstart"/>.
  </answer>
 </qandaentry>
 
 <qandaentry>
  <question>
   <para>
    What existing core infrastructure services are required or recommended to run the &productname; platform? 
   </para>
  </question>
  <answer>
   <para>
    On-premise you need to run the following services:
   </para>
   <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>DNS</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>
       The service is required for the &admin_node; and the &kmaster; as the nodes must have resolvable A entries that can be resolved within the L2 subnet as well as from any client accessing the cluster. &kworker;s are able to resolve the &kmaster; by using the hosts file entry that is managed by &salt;. The hosts file entry points to the &kmaster; <literal>fqdn</literal> entered into &dashboard;. Resolvable FQDNS are no longer required for &kworker;s as &salt; keeps the hosts file up to date with a reference for each node to every other node's unique hostname (using the &sminion; ID). &productabbr; uses <literal>&lt;saltminionID&gt;.infra.caasp.local </literal> for referencing all nodes.
      </para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>DHCP</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>
      Is recommended for large-scale clusters. As &salt; manages cluster nodes hosts files there is no need to use static IP addresses. Ensure that DNS entries for the &admin_node; and the &kmaster; are always correct and up-to-date. For this purpose, the DHCP server can be configured to automatically update the DNS server  for each host name.
      </para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>NTP</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>
      The installer asks for an NTP server address. As &suse; does not have a corporate subdomain alias in <literal>pool.ntp.org</literal>, you need to choose NTP servers for your region or use your company own NTP servers (required for clusters that do not have external Internet access). The &admin_node; runs <literal>ntpd</literal>, other cluster nodes run <literal>systemd-timesyncd</literal> daemon configured to point to the &admin_node;
      </para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
  </answer>
 </qandaentry>
</qandaset>
 
 </article>
